Guide to the Phoebe Jacobs Jazz collection,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Jazz Musicians
  - Subseries III.4: Ella Fitzgerald
    - Sub-subseries III.4.2: Clippings
      - Newspaper articles concerning Ella Fitzgerald, unidentified sources, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 page 2 pages photocopies ) (Box 6, Folder 121)
      - Christian Science Monitor Quote regarding Ella Fitzgerald from Phoebe Jacobs, [n.p.], 14 August 1990, (1 page photocopy ) (Box 15, Folder 277)
      - "Two-day festival in April will honor Ella Fitzgerald", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 page photocopy ) (Box 15, Folder 278)
        [Unidentified source, date]
      - Los Angeles Herald Examiner "Singing praises of Ella", Los Angeles, CA, 1 May 1989, (1 page photocopy ) (Box 15, Folder 279)
      - Daily News Ella Fitzgerald feature in column "Suzy", New York, 10 October 1980, (1 page photocopy ) (Box 15, Folder 280)
      - Press release for video release "Ella Fitzgerald: Something to Live For", [n.p.], 18 October 1999, (2 pages t.ms. ) (Box 15, Folder 281)
    - Sub-subseries III.4.3: Photographs
      - Fitzgerald, Ella The Mike Douglas Show Photograph: live performance, [n.p.], June 1975, (1 black and white, 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 15, Folder 282)
        [With Godfrey Cambridge]
      - Ella Fitzgerald Photograph, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 6, Folder 122)
        [At table with unidentified crowd]
      - Photographs of Ella Fitzgerald taken at Ralph Watkins' Basin St. East, New York, 1960 and 1961, (2 photographs 3 1/2 x 5 inches ) (Box 6, Folder 123)
        [With Trini Lopez and Billy Daniels]
      - Ella Fitzgerald Miscellaneous items concerning Ella Fitzgerald: television schedule and addressed envelope; newspaper clipping, [n.p.], (1 envelope 2 pages ) (Box 15, Folder 283)
        [Clipping is notice of article with graphic; article not included]
      - Fitzgerald, Ella Publicity photographs, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 black and white, 7 x 9 1/4 inches ) (Box 18, Folder 369)
      - Fitzgerald, Ella Color slides, [n.p.], [n.d.], (3 2 x 2 inches ) (Box 18, Folder 370)
        [Youthful Fitzgerald performing live [not positively identified]]
      - Fitzgerald, Ella Exhibition announcement "Ella Fitzgerald: First Lady of Song", National Museum of American History, Smithsonian Institution: Washington D.C., 19 March 1998, (1 p.c. ) (Box 18, Folder 371)
        [Announcement on back of Fitzgerald postcard]
  - Subseries III.5: Dizzy Gillespie
    - Quincy Jones Written memories of Dizzy Gillespie, Los Angeles, 6 January 1992, (2 pages t.ms. ) (Box 3, Folder 93)
      [Facsimile sent from Rogers and Cowan, Inc. in Los Angeles]
  - Subseries III.6: Benny Goodman
    - Frazier, George Biographical write up on Goodman, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 pages t.ms. ) (Box 6, Folder 130)
    - Lissner, John Magazine article "Benny Goodman: The Swing Era +40", American Way, August 1975, (4 pages ) (Box 6, Folder 131)
    - Newspaper clippings regarding Benny Goodman, [n.p.] & New York, [n.d.]; 1961, (2 pages photocopies ) (Box 6, Folder 132)
      [Containing 9 clippings]
    - Photographs: negative of Benny Goodman and snapshot of Rachel Goodman with Phoebe Jacobs, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 black and white negative 4 x 3 inches 1 color photograph, 4 x 4 inches ) (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - Goodman, Benny Concert announcement for ongoing shows at Freedomland, [n.p.], July 20-25 [n.y.], (1 item ) (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - Goodman, Benny Program: Carnegie Hall 40th anniversary concert program, New York, 1978, (1 vol. bd. ) (Box 6, Folder 135)
      [Goodman featured artist]
  - Subseries III.7: Peggy Lee
    - Photocopies of biography, recording lists, and flyer for art exhibition for Lee's daughter, Nickie Lee, [v.p.], [n.c.]1947-1999, (1 folder, photocopies ) (Box 6, Folder 147)
    - Barbour, Dave Daily News Obituary listing of Peggy Lee's divorced husband, New York, 13 December 1965, (1 clipping ) (Box 15, Folder 290)
    - Stein, Jeannine Los Angeles Times Article "S' Wonderful: Society of Singers and Friends Galore Salute Jazzy Peggy Lee", Beverly Hills, Los Angeles, 11 May 1994, (1 page photocopy ) (Box 15, Folder 291)
    - The Times Article "That's not all there is, says Miss Lee", [n.p.], 15 June 1994, (1 page photocopy ) (Box 15, Folder 292)
    - Elwood, Philip Article "Peggy Lee Steals Carnegie Hall", San Fransisco Examiner, San Fransisco, CA, 27 June 1995, (9 photocopies ) (Box 15, Folder 293)
    - Snow, Shauna Column item "Peggy Lee Hospitalized", [n.p.], 4 November 1998, (1 page ) (Box 15, Folder 294)
    - Incomplete record review of "The Complete Peggy Lee and June Christy Capitol Transcription Sessions", [n.p.], May 1999, (1 page photocopy ) (Box 15, Folder 295)
      [Source unidentified]
    - Los Angeles Times Article concerning Peggy Lee, "One Last Goodbye", Los Angeles, CA, 5 February 2002, (1 page ) (Box 15, Folder 296)
      [Memorial article mentions Phoebe Jacobs]
    - Billboard Magazine Cover article "Miss Peggy Lee: May 26, 1920-January 21, 2002", [n.p.], 9 February 2002, (1 vol. bd. ) (Box 15, Folder 297)
    - Haran, Mary Cleere Article "How Peggy Lee Changed My Life", Modern Maturity, January-February 1999, (4 pages ) (Box 15, Folder 298)
    - Feather, Leonard Article "Singers Salute Peggy Lee in Song and Celluloid", Los Angeles Times, [n.d.], (2 pages photocopies ) (Box 15, Folder 299)
    - Articles "Peggy Lee Has Shining Hour In a Dazzling Performance" and "Jazz Pop Lives with Lee, Torme"; "Lee's ever the enchantress" with "Peggy Lee and Mel Torme Offer Mystery and Precision, New York, [n.d.], (1 page photocopy 10 photocopies 12, photocopies ) (Box 15, Folder 300)
      [Sources and dates unidentified]
    - Excerpt of published letters with references to Peggy Lee, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 pages ) (Box 15, Folder 301)
      [Unidentified date and source]
  - Subseries III.8: Sy Oliver
    - Clark, Lillian Vita, obituary, and articles regarding the wife of Sy Oliver, [n.p.], (1 folder ) (Box 5, Folder 112)
  - Subseries III.9: Sarah Vaughn
    - Photographs, biography, press quotes, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 black and white photographs,8 x 10 inches 3 page t.ms. ) (Box 6, Folder 146)
- Series IV: Publicity Material
  - Assorted press releases, newspaper clippings, and faxes regarding "Save America's Treasures." Includes one color photocopy of a photograph of Hillary Rodham Clinton with children at the event; Program from "Save America's Treasures"; Program notes from the event, December 1998, (1 folder ) (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - New York Public Library "Jazz: A curriculum enhancement project of the New York Public Library for the Performing Arts": materials, New York, Summer 1993, (1 folder ) (Box 4, Folder 96)
    [Educational program made possible by the Louis Armstrong Foundation.]
  - Lincoln Center Clippings, press releases and programs regarding Jazz at Lincoln Center events and educational series, New York, [n.d.] 1993-2000, (1 folder ) (Box 5, Folder 113)
  - Lincoln Center Essentially Ellington series: High School Jazz Band Competition and Festival: press clippings, New York, 13-15 May 2000, (1 folder ) (Box 5, Folder 114)
  - Lincoln Center Jazz at Lincoln Center: Student Musician's Guide to Jazz, New York, 2000, (78 pages ) (Box 5, Folder 117)
  - Columbia University Conference notes: Jazz Study Group Fall 1999 Meeting, "Jazz Singers", New York, 6-7 November 1999, (1 vol. bd. ) (Box 6, Folder 152)
    [Contains schedule, readings from periodicals, and handwritten notes.]
  - The Goodman Theatre Program for theatre run "Play On!"; media kit with press releases, Chicago, IL, 19 June-Aug 1998, (1 program 1, vol. bd. ) (Box 6, Folder 153)
  - Assorted catalogs and publicity material from schools, music programs, and publications, [n.p.], 1990s, (13 items ) (Box 6, Folder 148)
  - New York Public Library for the Performing Arts Publicity packet for "Jazz" presentation and show; season schedule, library building guide, and color poster, New York, June 24-September 30, 1993, (20 slides, 1 folder ) (Box 6, Folder 149)
  - Runyon Cancer Fund, Meals for Millions, and Girl Town Concert program for benefit program, Basin Street East: New York, 30 October 1961, (1 vol. bd. 1 invitation ) (Box 15, Folder 302)
    [Quincy Jones, musical director]
  - Davis, Gene Gene Davis Group Press release "A Narrative Outline for Broadcast Production Consideration", New York, 21 July 1998, (2 pages facsimile ) (Box 15, Folder 303)
    [Proposal for televised documentary on Peggy Lee]
  - Peggy Lee Fan Club Newsletter "Fever!" Issue 20, Vol. 5, San Leandro, CA, June 1999, (1 vol. bd. ) (Box 15, Folder 304)
  - Peggy Lee Fan Club Newsletter "Fever!" Issue 23, Volume 6, San Leandro, CA, Spring 2000, (1 vol. bd. ) (Box 15, Folder 305)
  - Press release regarding honorary doctorate, Jamestown College: Jamestown, ND, 1 May 2000, (4 page photocopies ) (Box 15, Folder 306)
    [Peggy Lee was born in Jamestown, ND]
  - W3 Public Relations Press release: "Latin Ala Lee" Marks Timely Re-release from Singer Peggy Lee", Los Angeles, CA, 5 May 2002, (2 pages ) (Box 15, Folder 307)
  - Kaiser, Steve Flyer for Lee Tribute by jazz singer Kaiser, Chez Suzette: New York, 24 February 2002, (1 page ) (Box 15, Folder 308)
  - Published promotional items: realty package for Lee's French Regency Villa; souvenir Lee program with printed materials and photographs; Peggy Lee folder; ticket stub, Los Angeles; New York; [n.p.], 28 June 1979; [n.d.], (4 items ) (Box 15, Folder 309)
    [Ticket stub performance with Buddy Rich]
  - Miscellaneous items: registration for fan club; program announcement, [n.p.], (2 items ) (Box 15, Folder 310)
  - Receipts for purchases, [n.p.], (5 items ) (Box 15, Folder 311)
    [Dates unclear]
  - Peggy Lee publicity photographs, [n.p.], circa 1950s, (2 black and white, 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 15, Folder 312)
  - Publicity photographs of Peggy Lee, [n.p.], circa early 1960s, (6 black and white, 8 x 10 inches, 1 black and white, 5 x 4 1/2 inches ) (Box 15, Folder 313)
  - Basin Street East Postcards featuring Peggy Lee, New York, circa early 1960s, (4 black and white p.c. ) (Box 15, Folder 314)
  - Publicity photographs of Peggy Lee, [n.p.], circa 1960s, (7 black and white, 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 15, Folder 315)
  - Publicity photographs of Peggy Lee, [n.p.], circa 1970s, (7 black and white, 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 15, Folder 316)
  - Publicity photographs of Peggy Lee, [n.p.], circa 1970s, (3 black and white, 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 15, Folder 317)
  - Publicity photographs of Peggy Lee, [n.p.], circa 1970s-1980s, (9 black and white, 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 15, Folder 318)
  - Publicity photographs of Peggy Lee, [n.p.], circa 1980s, (2 black and white, 8 x 10 inches, 1 color, 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 15, Folder 319)
  - Publicity photograph of Peggy Lee, [n.p.], circa 1990s, (1 black and white, 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 15, Folder 320)
  - Judy Garland Show Photograph of television broadcast with Garland and Peggy Lee, [n.p.], 1 December 1963, (1 black and white photograph, 3 1/2 x 5 1/4 inches ) (Box 15, Folder 321)
  - Peggy Lee at memorial service for Louis Armstrong, New York, July 1971, (1 black and white, 4 x 5 inches ) (Box 15, Folder 322)
    [With manager Brian Panella; Lee sang "The Lord's Prayer" and "Ave Maria"]
  - CBS Production photograph of Lee with band on televised Armstrong tribute, New York, 8 July 1971, (1 black and white, 10 x 12 inches ) (Box 15, Folder 323)
    [With Buddy Rich, Tyre Glenn, Bobby Hackett, Dizzy Gillespie, Milt Hinton, Walter Kronkite]
  - Peggy Lee with Lucille Armstrong and Earl Wilson, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 black and white, 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 15, Folder 325)
  - Hollywood Bowl Snapshot of Lee with "Smitty", Hollywood, CA, August 1995, (1 color, 2 1/2 x 3 1/4 inches ) (Box 15, Folder 326)
  - Photograph of Peggy Lee, [n.p.], circa 1980s, (1 s. black and white, 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 15, Folder 327)
    [Signed "Love Peggy Lee" in silver ink]
  - [Primavera Lounge] Photograph of Peggy Lee, [n.p.], circa 1980s, (1 s. black and white, 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 15, Folder 328)
    [Signed in silver ink "To Bert, wishing you luck, Peggy Lee"]
  - Ralph Watkins' Basin Street East Snapshot of marquee announcing Peggy Lee, New York, [n.d.], (1 color, 3 1/2 x 3 1/2 inches ) (Box 15, Folder 329)
  - Miller, Mitchell Signed notes, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 a.n.s. ) (Box 15, Folder 330)
    [1) signed "Only because I love you," recipient unidentified. 2) signed "Dearest Phoebe, All my love, Mitch" ]
  - American Society for Composers, Authors, and Publishers Miscellaneous printed material (Box 20)
  - Carnegie Hall Miscellaneous printed materal (Box 20)
    [Some material concerns jazz concerts at Carnegie Hall]
  - Center for Black Music Research Miscellaneous printed material concerning the Center for Black Music Research (Box 20)
  - Center for Jazz Studies at Columbia University Miscellaneous printed material, news paper clippings, and news articles from internet sources (Box 20)
    [Material includes information on some classes taught at Center for Jazz Studies]
  - Jazz at Lincoln Center Miscellaneous printed material concernig jazz programs at Lincoln Center (Box 20)
  - Queens College of the City University of New York Reading packet for the course The Neighborhood Arts Project (Box 20)
  - Queens Museum of Art Printed material concerning "Organizational Background" of the Queens Museum of Art (Box 21)
  - National Music Center & Museum Printed publicity release concerning the museum (Box 21)
  - Miller, Norma Publicity material concerning Swingin' at the Savoy: The Home of Happy Feet, the national book tour, (1 photocopy packet ) (Box 21)
  - The Julliard School Facsimile to Phoebe Jacobs from Paula Mlyn concernring the the acceptance of the first 18 jazz musicians in to the new Julliard Institute for Jazz Studies, as well as other information concerning jazz programs at The Julliard School (Box 21)
  - National Black Sports & Entertainment Hall of Fame Miscellaneous printed material and newspaper clippings (Box 21)
  - New York Youth Symphony Miscellaneous printed material (Box 21)
  - Schomburg Center for Research in Black Culture Miscellaneous printed material (Box 21)
  - Society of Singers Printed material and newspaper clippings regarding awards given by the Society of Singers (Box 21)
  - Songwriters' Hall of Fame Invitation and program from 2000 induction ceremony (Box 21)
  - Upper Manhattan Empowerment Zone Photocopies and original paper work relating to the Louis Armstrong Educational Foundation's donation to the Upper Manhattan Empowerment Zone (Box 21)
  - Universal Jazz Coalition, Inc. UJC Cobi's Music News and a letter regarding participation IAJE Convention, Oct. 25 - Nov. 20, 2001 and August 2000 (Box 21)
  - Friars Club Photocopied newspaper articles, program from January 1980, and invitation to the Lifetime Achievement Honors ceremony for 1998 (Box 21)
    [Lionel Hampton awarded the Creative Achievement Award in 1998]
- Series V: Promotional Materials
  - News for Friends of Leonard Bernstein Two newsletters; concert announcment of Bernstein's work, New York, 1972-1998, (3 items ) (Box 16, Folder 331)
  - Bono, Sonny New York Times; ABC Radio Newspaper clipping and internet reports on death of Bono, New York, 11 January 1998, (3 items ) (Box 16, Folder 332)
  - Brubeck, Dave Newsletter; travel itinerary; performance announcements, New York, 2000-2001, (4 items ) (Box 16, Folder 333)
  - Burns, Ken PBS Press materials for Burns' documentary "Jazz", [n.p.], January 2001, (1 folder ) (Box 16, Folder 334)
  - Recht, MikeAP Review of Ken Burns' "Jazz" downloaded from Internet, Walpole NH, [n.d.], (3 page print-out ) (Box 16, Folder 335)
  - Leonard, John New York Magazine Article: "All That Jazz: Ken Burns' jammy marathon history of jazz pays due homage to a century of American music", New York, 8 January 2001, (1 vol. bd. ) (Box 16, Folder 336)
    [Page 56.]
  - Clinton, Bill Articles and flyers regarding Clinton's office location in Harlem, New York, July 2001, (4 items ) (Box 16, Folder 337)
  - Crouch, Stanley Articles by and about Crouch, [v.p.], 1995-2002; [n.d.], (1 folder ) (Box 16, Folder 338)
  - Goodman, Benny Article, program announcement, unused card with Goodman graphic, New York; [n.p.], 1979; 1986, (3 items ) (Box 16, Folder 339)
  - Kennedy, John F. Jr. Time Magazine; Newsweek Articles regarding death of Kennedy and Carolyn Bessette Kennedy, [n.p.], July 1999, (2 vol. bd. ) (Box 16, Folder 340)
  - Kravitz, Lenny Press photo; folder, Tommy Hilfiger advertisement, [n.p.], 2000; [n.d.], (3 items ) (Box 16, Folder 341)
  - Marsalis, Wynton Newspaper clippings and press releases; postcard, [v.p.], 1990-2002; [n.d.], (1 folder ) (Box 16, Folder 342)
  - Murray, Albert Articles and book excerpts by the scholar, [n.p.], 1971-1998; [n.d.], (10 items ) (Box 16, Folder 343)
  - Sinatra, Frank Newspaper and periodical clippings, [v.p.], 1997-1998; [n.d.], (1 folder ) (Box 16, Folder 344)
  - Vaughn, Sarah Photocopies of articles; concert announcement, New York, 1980; [n.d.], (1 folder ) (Box 16, Folder 345)
  - Vaughn, Sarah Photograph and postcards, [n.p.], 1959; [n.d.], (1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches, 2 p.c. ) (Box 16, Folder 346)
  - Baker, Josephine Photocopy of article, [n.p.], (1 page ) (Box 16, Folder 347)
    [No date or source]
  - Newspaper clippings marking deaths of American icons and others (not all jazz related), [v.p.], 1995-2001; [n.d.], (9 items ) (Box 16, Folder 348)
    [Includes Perry Como, Sarah McCorckle, and Anthony Quinn (all 2001); and Henry Youngman (1998)]
  - Reaves-Phillips, Sandra Press kit and CD "A Tribute to Mahalia Jackson", [n.p.], 2000, (1 folder ) (Box 17, Folder 349)
  - Stewart, Bob Press kit, [n.p.], 2000, (1 folder ) (Box 17, Folder 350)
  - Warren, Fran Press kit and cassette tapes; photographs, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 folder, 2 cassettes 4, black and white photographs, 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 17, Folder 351)
  - Promotional materials by various artists arranged by last name, [n.p.], (1 folder ) (Box 17, Folder 352)
  - Programs and materials for jazz festivals and events arranged by date, [v.p.], 1974-1999, (1 folder ) (Box 17, Folder 353)
  - Programs and materials for jazz festivals and events arranged by date, [v.p.], 2000-2001, (1 folder ) (Box 17, Folder 354)
  - Programs and materials for jazz festivals and events arranged by date, [v.p.], 2001-2002, (1 folder ) (Box 17, Folder 355)
  - Programs and materials for undated jazz festivals and events, [v.p.], [n.d.], (1 folder ) (Box 17, Folder 356)
  - Miscellaneous community events (not jazz related), [v.p.], 1979-2001; [n.d.], (1 folder ) (Box 17, Folder 357)
  - Carney, Harry Publicity photographs, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 black and white, 9 1/4 x 7 inches, 1 black and white, 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 18, Folder 360)
    [Includes unidentified ensemble]
  - Carney, Harry Color slides, [n.p.], [n.d.], (9 2 x 2 inches ) (Box 18, Folder 361)
    [With Harold Russell;]
  - Hall, Adelaide Color snapshot, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 4 x 6 inches ) (Box 18, Folder 372)
  - Horne, Lena Publicity photographs with unidentified artist, [n.p.], [n.d.], (3 black and white, 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 18, Folder 373)
  - Bushkin, Joe Press kit, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 folder ) (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Lincoln Center Jazz at Lincoln Center: promotional materials for proposed construction, New York, 2000, (33 pages bd. 1 folder ) (Box 5, Folder 116)
  - Lincoln Center Essentially Ellington: Band Director Academy, New York, 14-17 June 2000, (1 folder ) (Box 5, Folder 115)
  - Lincoln Center Teacher/Parent Manual: Louis Armstrong Jazz Curriculum with instructional sound recordings, New York, September 1999, (1 folder, 2 compact discs ) (Box 5, Folder 118)
  - Queens Library Flyers decribing jazz related holdings at the library, Queens, New York, [n.d.], (14 flyers, 1 page ) (Box 12, Folder 212)
  - The John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts Folder containing publicity material (Box 21)
  - The Jazz Foundation of America Miscellaneous printed promotional material concerning the Jazz Foundation of America (Box 21)
- Series VI: Miscellaneous
  - Newspaper clippings, [v.p.], 2000, (1 folder ) (Box 6, Folder 150)
    [Jazz related topics; primarily from New York]
  - Photocopies of newspaper clippings, [v.p.], 1967-2000, (1 folder ) (Box 6, Folder 151)
  - Miscellaneous photocopies of correspondence, press releases, and announcements, [v.p.], [n.d.]; 1986-2000, (1 folder ) (Box 6, Folder 154)
  - Meyer, Brian "Restaurateur fulfills his entrepreneurial dream"; incomplete article, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 pages photocopies ) (Box 14, Folder 250)
    [Articles with incomplete information]
  - The New Yorker "Jazz: An Only", New York, NY, 15 May 1978, (2 pages ) (Box 14, Folder 251)
  - Dance, Stanley Book: Giants of Jazz, Time-Life Records: Alexandria, VA, 1978, (1 vol. bd. ) (Box 14, Folder 260)
  - Fadeles, Jon Sketch drawings, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 drawings s. ) (Box 12, Folder 210)
    [Medium appears to be crayon on paper]
  - Articles and book on music therapy, [v.p.], 1999-2000, (4 items ) (Box 12, Folder 213)
    [Includes flyer from The Louis and Lucille Armstrong Music Therapy Program.]
  - Miscellaneous printed material concerning education (Box 22)
  - Miscellaneous clippings - newspaper and magazine (Box 22)
  - Miscellaneous manuscript material (Box 22)
  - Miscellaneous memorabilia including posters and deframed awards presented to Louis Armstrong and Lionel Hampton from the National Black Sports and Entertainment Hall of Fame (Box Flat Box 368)
  - Jazz posters (Box 7)